Guide to the Herman F. Mark Collection, 1918-2013 RG.002
Poly Archives at Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology
- Series IV: Publications
  - Subseries G: Monographs and notebooks
    - "Volume 2: Test Methods, Specifications, and Standards" Fire Safety Aspects of Polymeric Materials series, 1979 (Item 21)
    - "Volume 2: Test Methods, Specifications, and Standards" Fire Safety Aspects of Polymeric Materials series (copy 2), 1979 (Item 22)
    - "Volume 4: Fire Dynamics and Scenarios" Fire Safety Aspects of Polymeric Materials series, 1978 (Item 23)
    - "Volume 5: Elements of Polymer Fire Safety and Guide to the Designer" Fire Safety Aspects of Polymeric Materials series, 1979 (Item 24)
    - "Volume 6: Aircraft: Civil and Military" Fire Safety Aspects of Polymeric Materials series, 1977 (Item 25)
    - "Volume 7: Buildings" Fire Safety Aspects of Polymeric Materials series, 1979 (Item 26)
    - "Volume 9: Ships" Fire Safety Aspects of Polymeric Materials series, 1980 (Item 27)
    - "Volume 10: Mines and Bunkers" Fire Safety Aspects of Polymeric Materials series, 1980 (Item 28)
    - "High Polymeric Reactions Their Theory and Practice," High Polymers Vol. III, 1941 (Item 29)
    - "Mechanism of Polymer Reactions," High Polymers Vol. III, 1954 (Item 30)
    - "Natural and Synthetic High Polymers," High Polymers Vol. IV, 1942 (Item 31)
    - "Natural and Synthetic High Polymers," High Polymers Vol. IV, Second Edition, 1950 (Item 32)
    - "Cellulose and Cellulose Derivatives" High Polymers Vol. V, 1946 (Item 33)
    - "Cellulose and Cellulose Derivatives" Part I, High Polymers Vol. V, 1954 (Item 34)
    - "Cellulose and Cellulose Derivatives" Part II, High Polymers Vol. V, 1954 (Item 35)
    - "Cellulose and Cellulose Derivatives" Part III, High Polymers Vol. V (2 copies), 1955 (Item 36)
    - "Cellulose and Cellulose Derivatives" Part IV, High Polymers Vol. V (2 copies), 1971 (Item 37)
    - "Cellulose and Cellulose Derivatives" Part V, High Polymers Vol. V (2 copies), 1971 (Item 38)
    - "Phenoplasts: Their Structure, Properties and Chemical Technology," High Polymers VII, 1947 (Item 39)
    - "Emulsion Polymerization" High Polymers Vol. IX, 1955 (Item 40)
    - "Analytical Chemistry of Polymers" Part II, High Polymers Vol. XII, 1962 (Item 41)
    - "Analytical Chemistry of Polymers" Part III, High Polymers Vol. XII, 1962 (Item 42)
    - "Polyethers" Part I, High Polymers Vol. XIII, 1963 (Item 43)
    - "Polyethers" Part III, High Polymers Vol. XIII (2 copies), 1962 (Item 44)
    - "Polymer Chemistry of Synthetic Elastomers" Part I, High Polymers Vol. XXIII, 1968 (Item 45)
    - "Polymer Chemistry of Synthetic Elastomers" Part II, High Polymers Vol. XXIII, 1969 (Item 46)
    - "Vinyl and Diene Monomers" Part 2, High Polymers Vol. XXIV, 1971 (Item 47)
    - "Vinyl and Diene Monomers" Part 3, High Polymers Vol. XXIV (2 copies), 1971 (Item 48)
    - "Cyclic Monomers," High Polymers Vol. XXVI, 1972 (Item 49)
    - "Allyl Compounds and Their Polymers (Including Polyolefins), High Polymers Vol. XXVIII, 1973 (Item 50)
    - "Fracture Processes in Polymeric Solids," ed. Bernard Rosen, 1964 (Item 51)
    - "Proceedings 3rd Annual Conference on the Physics of Compound Semiconductor Interfaces," ed. Mark, 1976 (Item 52)
    - "Proceedings 5th Annual Conference on the Physics of Compound Semiconductor Interfaces," ed. Mark, 1978 (Item 53)
    - "Concepts, Critiques and Comments: Wide and Varied" A Festschrift in Honor of David Rose, 1976 (Item 54)
    - "Selected Papers of Turner Alfrey," ed. R. Boyer and H. Mark, 1986 (Item 55)
    - "Power & Security" by Edward Teller, Hans Mark, and John S. Foster, Jr. (inscribed to the Geheimrath from Hans), 1976 (Item 56)
    - "Crystal Structure and Chemical Constitution: A General Discussion held by the Faraday Society", 1929 March (Item 57)
    - "Organic Thin Films and Surfaces: Directions for the Nineties" ed. by Abraham Ulman, 1995 (Item 58)
    - "The Blue Nile" by Alan Moorehead, 1962 (Item 59)
    - "Matthews' Textile Fibers" Sixth Edition, ed. by H. R. Mauersberger, 1954 (Item 60)
    - "Natural and Synthetic High Polymers" by K. H. Meyer, 1942 (Item 61)
    - "The Effects of Ionizing Radiation on Natural and Synthetic High Polymers," by Frank Bovey (introduction by Herman Mark), 1958 (Item 62)
    - "Stress-Strain Behavior of Elastic Materials" by O.H. Varga (introduction by Herman Mark and Edmund Immergut), 1966 (Item 63)
    - "Molecular Weight Distributions in Polymers" by Leighton Peebles (introduction by Herman Mark and Edmund Immergut), 1971 (Item 64)
    - "Macromolecular Reviews" Vol. 10, Journal of Polymer Science, ed. A. Peterlin, 1975 (Item 65)
    - "Fiber Structure and Properties," Journal of Applied Polymer Science: Applied Polymer Symposia 33, ed. J.L. White, 1976 (Item 66)
    - "Long-Term Properties of Polymers and Polymeric Materials," Journal of Applied Polymer Science: Applied Polymer Symposia 33, ed. B. Ranby and J.F. Rabek, 1976 (Item 67)
    - "Commodity and Engineering Plastics," Journal of Applied Polymer Science: Applied Polymer Symposia 36, ed. N. Platzer, 1981 (Item 68)
    - "Symposium on Cellulose and Wood as Future Chemical Feedstocks and Sources of Energy, and General Papers," Journal of Applied Polymer Science: Applied Polymer Symposia 37, ed. A Sarko, 1982 (Item 69)
    - "Chemistry and Technology of Rubber," Journal of Applied Polymer Science: Applied Polymer Symposia 39, ed. A. Vidal and J.B. Donnet, 1982 (Item 70)
    - "U.S.-Japan Seminar on Polymer Liquid Crystals," Journal of Applied Polymer Science: Applied Polymer Symposia 41, ed. J.L. White and S. Onogi, 1983 (Item 71)
    - "Advances in Preparation and Charaterization of Multiphase Polymer Systems," Journal of Applied Polymer Science: Applied Polymer Symposia 60, ed. R.J. Ambrose and S.L. Aggarwal, 1977 (Item 72)
    - "Unsolved Problems of Co- and Graft Polymerization," Journal of Applied Polymer Science: Applied Polymer Symposia 64, ed. O. Vogl and C.I. Simionescu, 1976 (Item 73)
    - "Microcalorimetry of Macromolecules," Journal of Applied Polymer Science: Applied Polymer Symposia 69, ed. B. Sedlacek, C.G. Overberger, H.F. Mark, 1979 (Item 74)
    - "Polymers with Unusual Properties," Journal of Applied Polymer Science: Applied Polymer Symposia 70, ed. C.W. Allen, 1982 (Item 75)
    - "High Temperature and Flame-Resistant Fibers," Journal of Applied Polymer Science: Applied Polymer Symposia 20, ed. J. Preston and J. Economy, 1973 (Item 76)
    - "Luminescence from Biological and Synthetic Macromolecules Eighth Katzir Conference," ed. H. Morawetz and I.Z. Steinberg, 1981 (Item 77)
    - "Handbook of Fiber Science and Technology: Volume I," ed. M. Lewin and S.B. Sello, 1983 (Item 78)
    - "Handbook of Fiber Science and Technology: Volume II," ed. M. Lewin and S.B. Sello, 1983 (Item 79)
    - "Polymer Characterization," ed. B.J. Hunt and M.I. james, 1993 (Item 80)
    - "Free-Radical Polymerisation," ed. C.H. Bamford and C.F.H. Tipper, 1976 (Item 81)
    - "Monomeric Acrylic Esters," by E.H. Riddle, 1954 (Item 82)
    - "Handbook of Composite Reinforcements," ed. S.M. Lee, 1993 (Item 83)
    - "Elementary Crystallography," by M.J. Buerger, 1956 (Item 84)
    - "Journal of Polymer Science," Vol. 51, No. 156, 1961 June (Item 85)
    - "Proceedings of the Robert A. Welch Foundation 39th Conference on Chemical Research Nanophase Chemistry", 1995 (Item 86)
    - "Theorie und Molekulare Deutung Technologischer Eigenschaften von Hochpolymeren Werkstoffen", 1956 (Item 87)
    - "Forty Years of Firsts: The Recollections of a Dow Corning Pioneer," E.L. Warrick, 1990 (Item 88)
    - "Fracture Processes in Polymeric Solids," ed. Bernard Rosen, 1964 (Item 89)
    - "Handbook of Organic Coatings: A Comprehensive Guide for the Coatings Industry," by Raymond Seymour and Herman Mark, 1990 (Item 90)
    - "Metal and Metalloid Amides: Syntheses, Structures, and Physical and Chemical Properties, 1980 (Item 91)
    - "Multicomponent Polymer Systems," ed., I.S. Miles and S. Rostami, 1992 (Item 92)
    - "Infrared Spectroscopy of Polymer Blends, Composites and Surfaces," by Andrew Garton, 1992 November 19 (Item 93)
    - "Rheology of Polymers," by G.V. Vinogradov and A.Ya. Malkin, 1979 (Item 94)
    - "Giant Molecules," by Herman Mark (4 copies), 1966 (Item 95)
    - "Stereospecific Catalysis and Stereoregular Addition Polymers Volume II" A Collection of the Original Papers by Prof. Guilio Natta and coworkers, circa 1958 (Item 96)
    - "Stereospecific Catalysis and Stereoregular Addition Polymers Volume III" A Collection of the Original Papers by Prof. Guilio Natta and coworkers, circa 1959 (Item 97)
    - "Stereospecific Catalysis and Stereoregular Addition Polymers Volume IV" A Collection of the Original Papers by Prof. Guilio Natta and coworkers, circa 1959 (Item 98)
    - Kaiser-Wilhelm-Institut fur Faserstoffchemic, undated (Item 99)
    - Polymer Science: Series A Chemistry Physics, Vol. 41 no. 12, 1999 December (Item 100)
    - "Nieder Osterriech", 1979 (Item 101)
    - "Textile Fibres under the X-rays" by W.T. Astbury, circa 1943 (Item 102)
    - "Mechanical Properties of Wood and Paper" ed. R. Meredith, 1953 (Item 103)
    - "Die physik der Hochpolymeren" by H.A. Stuart, 1955 (Item 104)
    - "Direct Use of the Sun's Energy" by Farrington Daniels, 1964 (Item 105)
    - "Progress in the Chemistry of Organic Natural Products" ed. L. Zechmeister, 1953 (Item 106)
    - "Partners in Progress: A Chapter in the American-Swedish Exchange of Knowledge" ed. A Kastrup and N.W. Olsson, 1977 (Item 107)
    - "Grundriss der Makromolekularen Chemic" by B. Vollmert, 1962 (Item 108)
    - "New Commercial Polymer 1969-1975" by H-G Elias, 1977 (Item 109)
    - "The Chain Photon Theory of matter and Energy" by R.L. Saxe, 1977 (Item 110)
    - "Progress in Polymer Science Japan: Volume 7" ed. T. Otsu, 1974 (Item 111)
    - "Lehrbuch der Theoretischen Physik" by G. Joos, 1934 (Item 112)
- Series V: Subject files
  Arrangement note
  These files were in a vertical file cabinet, which was moved from Professor Mark's office to Dibner Library some time in the 1990s. The cabinet contained two sets of alphabetized files, and although there is much overlap between the file names and date ranges between these two sets, Professor Mark's original order is maintained as two sets with the original dividers.
  - Subseries A: Green tab dividers, 1989-1992
    - A, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - ACS, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Aloma Chair, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Applicants, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Bauer house, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - C, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Contributions, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Library Contributions, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - D, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - E, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - F, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Felsinger, 1990-1992 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - G, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Gordon Conference, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Greve, 1990-1992 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - H, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - I, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Isovolta, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Interscience, 1990-1992 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - J, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Jelling, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - K, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Kiser, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - L, 1990-1992 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Leydig, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - LORD, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Mc, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - M, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Hans Mark- National Academy, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Mail Service, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - N, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Nominations, 1989-1991 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Novophalt, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - N.A.S., 1988-1992 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - National Patent, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Nominations, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - O, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Overberger, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Orders, undated (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - OMV, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 40)
    - P, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 41)
    - E. Pearce- Education Award, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 42)
    - Pearce-Flory Award, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 43)
    - Poly, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 44)
    - Poly President, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 45)
    - Publications, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 46)
    - Programs, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 47)
    - Positions, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 48)
    - Poly President Search, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 49)
    - Patents, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 50)
    - Petrovicki, 1990-1992 (Box 17, Folder 51)
    - R, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Reports, 1959-1966 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Recommendations, 1990-1991 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - S, 1990-1991 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Soviet, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Slides, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - T, 1990-1991 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Thesis- Foreign, 1991-1992 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - U, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - V, 1991-1992 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Visitors, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - W, 1990-1992 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Weizmann, 1990-1992 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - XYZ, 1991-1992 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Subseries B: Beige tab dividers, Bulk, 1989-1991; 1979-1991
    - A, 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Abstracts, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Abstracts [lectures], undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - ACS, 1988-1990 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Applicants, 1988-1990 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Alsted-LORD-Mark, 1989-1991 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - B, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Bauer House, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Bower Award, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - C, 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Contributions, 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - D, 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Donations, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Drafts, undated (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Dues, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - E, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - F, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Franklin Institute, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Felsinger, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - G, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Greve Foundation, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - H, 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Harvey Prize, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - I, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Isovolta, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Interscience, 1990-1991 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - J, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Jelling, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Kiser, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Kricheldorf Correspondence, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - L, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Leydig, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Lists, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - LORD, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - M, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - MMSO [Miscellaneous slides], undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - N, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - National Academy, 1987-1990 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - National patent, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Nominations, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Novophalt, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Overberger, 1988-1990 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - P, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Perkin Medal, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Programs, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Poly, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Poly-President, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Publications, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Polymer Science, 1976-2003 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - R, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Recommendations, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Resumes, undated (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Reports, undated (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Research Programs, 1960s (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Royalties, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - S, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Seeman Story, 1988-1989 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Seeman, Jeffrey, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Soviet Academy, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - T, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Thesis- Foreign, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - U, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - V, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - Visitors, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - W, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - Weizmann Institute, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - XYZ, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - February, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - March, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 45)
    - May, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 46)
    - July, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - August, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 48)
    - September, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - November, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 50)
- Series VI: Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn and the Polymer Research Institute
  - Subseries A: Mark Birthday Symposia and Festschrift
    Scope and Contents note
    Professor Mark received birthday letters, cards, and festschrift from Europe, Asia, North America, South America, and the Middle East. Notable well-wishers include President Ronald Reagan, Mayor Ed Koch, and Polytechnic's Bern Dibner.
    - 60th Birthday Symposium, 1955-1995 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - 70th Birthday Symposium invitations, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - 70th Birthday Symposium program, seating, and notes, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - 70th Birthday Symposium press release and photo, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - 70th Birthday Symposium publications photocopies, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - 75th Birthday Tribute- Herman Mark Chair Established, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Herman F. Mark Chair in Polymer Science, 1970 May 3 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - "Drive for Mark Chair Picks up Steam" article with 80th Birthday Symposium program, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - 80th Birthday Banquet programs, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - 80th Birthday planning and invitation list, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - 80th Birthday thank you cards, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - 80th Birthday newspaper clippings, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - The Herman F. Mark Chair in Polymer Science pamphlets, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - 85th Birthday Symposium "Polymers in the Service of Man", 1980 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Golden Anniversary Symposium: Celebrating the 50th Anniversary of the Ph.D. Program in Chemistry and the Birthdays of Herman Mark (90), Frederich Eirich (80), Herbert Morazwetz (70), 1985 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - 90th Birthday Symposium "Polymer Science in the Next Decade" invitations and program, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - 90th Birthday newspaper clippings and articles, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - 90th Birthday Symposium review, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - 90th Birthday letters and cards, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - 90th Birthday letters and cards, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - 90th Birthday letters and cards, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - 90th Birthday telegrams, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - 90th Birthday Symposium photographs, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - 95th Birthday Symposium program and ticket, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - 95th Birthday Symposium planning and invitation lists, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - 95th Birthday Symposium correspondence, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - 95th Birthday Symposium opening lecture draft, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - 96th Birthday letters, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - "Portrait of a Scientist: Twenty minutes of time in his office" by L. Schleiniger, 1976 January (Box 20, Item 1)
    - Birthday gift "Natur und Architektur", 1985 (Box 20, Item 2)
    - Birthday wishes from Mayor Koch (bound), 1985 May 6 (Box 20, Item 3)
    - Birthday wishes from The Association of Finnish Chemical Societies (bound), 1985 May 3 (Box 20, Item 4)
    - Grosse Goldene Ehrenzeichen mit dem Stern [Great Golden medal with Star] awarded by the Republic of Austria (in red binder with gold seal), 1985 April 22 (Box 20, Item 5)
    - 70th Birthday Celebration photo album, 1965 May (Box 20, Item 6)
    - "Perspective in Polymer Science: A Volume dedicated to Herman F. Mark on the occasion of his 70th birthday" ed. E. Proskauer, E. Immergut, C. Overberger, 1966 (Box 20, Item 7)
    - 90th Birthday Festschrift from The Polish Academy of Sciences: Centre of Molecular and Marcomolecular Studies (bound), 1985 April 12 (Box 20, Item 8)
    - 90th Birthday Festschrift from Die Österreichische Akademie der Wissenschaften [the Austrian Academy of Sciences], 1985 May 3 (Box 20, Item 9)
    - 90th Birthday Festschrift from the Chinese Chemical Society member and former student Qian Baogong, 1985 (Box 20, Item 10)
    - 90th Birthday Festschrift from the Chinese Chemical Society President Qian Renyuan, 1985 May (Box 20, Item 11)
    - 90th Birthday Festschrift from the Chinese Chemical Society member Liu Dagang, 1985 May (Box 20, Item 12)
    - 90th Birthday Festschrift from the Institute of Macromolecular Chemistry, Czechoslovak Academy of Science, 1985 (Box 20, Item 13)
    - "Polymer Science in the Next Decade: An International Symposium Honoring Herman F. Mark on his 90th Birthday" ed. O Vogl and E. Immergut, 1987 (Box 20, Item 14)
  - Subseries B: Mark Memorial Symposium and Scholarship Fund
    - Memorial Symposium planning materials (including photographs), 1992 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Memorial Symposium planning materials (S.M. Atlas), 1992 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Memorial Symposium "Polymers to the Year 2000 and Beyond" programs and booklets, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Memorial Symposium invitation lists and registration forms, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Memorial Symposium invitation lists and registration forms, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Memorial Symposium invitations and registration forms, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Memorial Symposium fax confirmation slips, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Mark Scholarship Fund donor lists, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Mark Scholarship Fund donor lists, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Mark Symposium and Fund thank you lists, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Memorial Symposium manuscripts and Wiley correspondence, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Subseries C: Events
    - Polymer Research Institute Symposia programs, Bulk, 1949-1966; 1949-1989 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn Symposia brochures, 1948-1967 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Symposium-Workshop, "Polymeric Materials and their use in Transportation," and project proposals, 1976-1977 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - "Polymer Synthesis in the 1980s" Symposium and Honorary Degree awarded to Prof. Carl S. Marvel (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Symposium in Memorial of Professor Aharon Katzir-Katchalsky, 1973 February 3 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Event Programs, 1966-1968 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Subseries D: News and Brochures
    - PRI and Polytechnic public relations, Bulk, 1961-1968; 1961-2003 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Press Releases, 1960-1966 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Report from Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1955-1956 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Polytechnic in Brief and Polytechnic News, 1968-2003 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - The Polytechnic Faculty News, Bulk, 1965-1971; 1957-1971 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - PRI and Polytechnic brochures, 1960s - 2000s (Box 21, Folder 23)
- Series VII: Photographs
  - Subseries A: Portraits
    - Herman Mark in Austrian officer's uniform, World War I, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Herman Mark in Rogers Hall office, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Herman Mark black and white portraits, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Herman Mark black and white portraits, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Herman Mark black and white portraits, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Herman Mark color portraits, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Herman Mark silhouette portrait, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Herman Mark black and white portraits with contact sheet, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Herman Mark color portrait contact sheet, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Herman Mark black and white portraits with negatives, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Herman Mark portrait photocopies, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Herman Mark Oversize portrait, undated (Box 30, Item 1)
  - Subseries B: Family and Friends